<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contents>
    <title dbid="657ae1eba789759594df07d9"><![CDATA[]]></title>
    <transcript>
        <text path="" id="0" dbid="657ae1eba789759594df07da"><![CDATA[]]></text>
    </transcript>
    <components>
        <section class="pb-0">
            <row class="flex-row mt-5 mobileOrder">
                <column sm="6" class="mt-5 " style="display: flex;
                align-items: end;
                justify-items: end;
                justify-content: start;">
                    <component type="image" src="module_02/panel_grx_Net_Zero_and_scopes2.png" class="mb-0">
                        <alt dbid="657ae1eba789759594df07bb"><![CDATA[]]></alt>
                    </component>
                </column>
                <column sm="6" style="display: flex;
                align-items: center;
                justify-items: center;
                justify-content: start;
                flex-direction:column;">
                    <component type="text">
                        <h3 class="" dbid="657ae1eba789759594df07bc"><![CDATA[Net Zero and scopes]]></h3>
                        <p dbid="657ae1eba789759594df07bd"><![CDATA[A net-zero target must cover direct and indirect emissions , i.e. supply chain emissions (scopes 1,2 and 3). Therefore, your entire value chain needs to be included in the scope of your net-zero target.]]></p>
                        <p dbid="657c6cbcfaacb07a98047e2a"><![CDATA[This is significant since scope 3 often represents the majority of emissions.]]></p>
                    </component>
                    <component type="panel" class="bkgColorDarkGreen">
                        <compent type="text">
                            <p dbid="65840beb0d8b57c01521c8af" element_imported="1.0"><![CDATA[<b>A value chain</b> is a business model that describes the full range of activities needed to create a product or service.]]></p>
                        </compent>
                    </component>
                </column>
            </row>
        </section>
        <section class="bkgColorLightGreen" bkgImage="footers/greensoftware_summary_footer.png">
            <row>
                <column sm_offset="2" sm="8">
                    <component type="text">
                        <ul>
                            <li dbid="657ae1eba789759594df07db"><![CDATA[<b>Scope 1 emissions</b> — This one covers the Green House Gas (GHG) emissions that a company makes directly — for example while running its boilers and vehicles.]]></li>
                            <li dbid="657ae1eba789759594df07dc"><![CDATA[<b>Scope 2 emissions</b> — These are the emissions an organisation makes indirectly – like when the electricity or energy it buys for heating and cooling buildings, is being produced on its behalf.]]></li>
                            <li dbid="657ae1eba789759594df07dd"><![CDATA[<b>Scope 3 emissions</b> — Now here’s where it gets tricky. In this category go all the emissions associated, not with the company itself, but that the organisation is indirectly responsible for, up and down its value chain. For example, from buying products from its suppliers, and from its products when customers use them. Emissions caused by the disposal of the products like hardware also becomes part of the scope 3 emissions. Emissions-wise, scope 3 is nearly always the big one.]]></li>
                        </ul>
                    </component>
                </column>
            </row>
        </section>
    </components>
</contents>