<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contents>
    <title dbid="657ae1eba789759594df081e"><![CDATA[Power usage effectiveness]]></title>
    <transcript>
        <text path="" id="0" dbid="657ae1eba789759594df081f"><![CDATA[]]></text>
    </transcript>
    <components>
        <section class="bkgColorLightGreen mb-0 pb-0">
            <row class="gap30">
                <column sm="12">
                    <component type="text" class="mb-4">
                        <h2 class="" dbid="657ae1eba789759594df0820"><![CDATA[Power usage effectiveness​]]></h2>
                        <p dbid="657ae1eba789759594df0821"><![CDATA[The Data Centre Industry uses the power usage effectiveness (PUE) metric developed by the green grid in 2006. Specifically, this relates to how much energy the computer equipment uses as compared to cooling and other overheads such as lighting and monitoring required to support the equipment.  ]]></p>
                        <p dbid="657ae1eba789759594df0822"><![CDATA[A PUE of 1.5 would be using 1 unit of energy for computing compared to 0.5 on cooling equipment. The typical range for PUE is between 1.0 and 2.0 with the lower being better. ]]></p>
                        <p dbid="6596c74102dd2cb62b72ac76"><![CDATA[Most traditional large data centres will be around 1.55 to 1.6 (reported as 1.58 for 2023 by independent research) due in part to the location of the data centre (a warmer temperature profile for a location will increase PUE). Some cloud providers are reporting their data centre PUE figures as better than 1.2 which is linked to the way the IT and cooling resilience is set up and in some cases where the Data Centres are located (in colder climates colder air can be used for free cooling most of the year and reduces the need for mechanical cooling altogether). ]]></p>
                    </component>
                    <component type="instruction" class="">
                        <text dbid="657ae1eba789759594df0825"><![CDATA[Select the buttons to find out more.]]></text>
                    </component>
                    <component type="BuildupCarousel" class="no-bkg text-top controls-outside pager-top ratio4x1 mb-0 text-gap" mode="fade">
                        <slide bkgImage="module_03/pue/power_usage_02.png">
                            <p dbid="657ae1eba789759594df0826"><![CDATA[So, for example, if your application consumed 10 kWh...]]></p>
                        </slide>
                        <slide bkgImage="module_03/pue/power_usage_03.png">
                            <p dbid="657ae1eba789759594df0827"><![CDATA[...and the PUE of the data centre where it is running is 1.5, then the actual consumption from the grid is 15 kWh.]]></p>
                        </slide>
                        <slide bkgImage="module_03/pue/power_usage_04.png">
                            <p dbid="657ae1eba789759594df0828"><![CDATA[5kWh goes towards the operational overhead of the data centre, and 10 kWh goes to the servers that are running your application.]]></p>
                        </slide>
                    </component>
                </column>
            </row>
            <!-- <row class="flex-row mt-5">
                <column sm="12" class="mb-0 pb-0" style="display: flex;
                align-items: end;
                justify-items: end;
                justify-content: start;">
                    <component type="image" class="pb-0 mb-0" src="module_03/power_usage.png">
                        <alt dbid="6576db05a8291e4d482a1ef8"><![CDATA[]]></alt>
                    </component>
                </column>
            </row> -->
        </section>
    </components>
</contents>